Guide to the Hunt Bradley papers, 1872-1982.
Bradley, Hunt papers, 1872-1982.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Hunt Bradley papers, 1872-1982, 1920-1982 (bulk)
41-2-1550
Horatio Hunt Bradley, 1904-1982.
10.5 cubic ft.,
Manuscripts, photographs, slides, printed matter, clippings, scrapbooks, broadsides, tape recordings, transcripts, historical data, correspndence, notes, records, costumes, mailings, abd materials.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Collection consists primarily of manuscript material for Bradley's book on the history of the Cornell Alumni Association, 1972, as well as numerous other items pertaining to Cornell history.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Cornell University Class of 1926.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Collection consists primarily of manuscript material for Bradley's book on the history of the Cornell Alumni Association, 1972; Cornell photographs, glass lantern slides, printed matter, clippings, scrapbooks, broadsides, and other Cornelliana; tape recordings and transcripts of former members of the Alumni Office staff, including Foster Coffin, Emmet Murphy, Ray Ashbery, Max Schmitt, Olive N. Snyder, Herman Krauss, Frances Egan, Walter K. Nield, Ho Ballou, Howard Stevenson, and Willard Kiggins; historical data concerning Cornell organizations including Quill and Dagger, Alpha Delta Phi, Cornell Alumni Fund, Cornell University Council, and Cornell Clubs of New York, New England, and Chicago; track team programs, correspondence, and travel information; personal correspondence; Her Honor Forever Maintain, by Bradley, 1973, and associated notes, manuscripts, and sources; "How to Conduct Class Reunions," a 1961 speech by Bradley; Class of 1926 reunion and fundraising materials, class mailings, and reunion costumes; records pertaining to other Cornell classes; and a cassette recording of Hunt Bradley's memorial service, 1982. Also, 1 bottle (empty) of Ballantine Burton Ale brewed for Hunt Bradley, 1946, and an evaluation of the contents, 1985.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Bradley, Hunt, 1904-1982.; Ashbery, Ray.; Ballou, Ho.; Coffin, Foster, 1890-1979.; Egan, Frances.; Kiggins, Willard.; Krauss, Herman.; Murphy, Emmet.; Nield, Walter K.; Schmitt, Max.; Snyder, Olive N.; Stevenson, Howard.; Alpha Delta Phi.; Cornell Club of Chicago.; Cornell Club of New England.; Cornell Club of New York.; Cornell University--Alumni and alumnae.; Cornell University--Societies, etc.; Cornell University. Class of 1926.; Cornell University. Alumni Association.; Cornell University. Alumni Office.; Cornell University. Council.; Quill and Dagger Society (Cornell University)
Subjects:
Class reunions.; Educational fund raising.; Fund raisers (Persons)
Form and Genre Terms:
Broadsides.; Lantern slides.; Manuscripts for publication.; Photographs.; Scrapbooks.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
Includes collection 4-2-1364.
CONTAINER LIST
- Personal
  - Moses Brown School - Track Miscellany, 1920-1922 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, Sept. 1921-Feb. 1922 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, Mar.-May 1922 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, July 1922-1923 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, Jan.-Apr. 1924 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, May 1924 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, June-Dec. 1924 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, Jan.-Apr. 1925 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, May-Nov. 1925 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, Jan.-June 1926 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, July 1926 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, Aug.-Oct. 1926 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1927-1933, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence - greeting cards (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Social Invitations, 1920s (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Bills and Receipts, ca. 1925-1930 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Quill and Dagger - miscellany, 1921-1930 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Alpha Delta Phi, 1922-1925 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Alpha Delta Phi, 1946-1960 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Alpha Delta Phi, 1955-1956 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, 1955-1970 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, 1971-1981 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Personal items
    - Passport, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Citation, certificate, 1927 (Folder 23)
    - Notes, 1940? (Folder 23)
    - Unidentified notebook, 1884 (Folder 23)
  - S.A.T.C., 1918 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Track
  - Cornell Track Miscellany, 1921-1970 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Cornell Track Miscellany (Box 1, Folder 26-29)
  - International Meet, July 1925 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Personal Expenses, England trip, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - England, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Travel Miscellany: bills, schedules, ticket (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Theatre programs, menus, 1870, 1926-1936 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Track Competition - Dope, 1923-1925 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - ICAAAA, 1925-1926 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Varsity Track Squad, 1925-1926 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Trials and Meets in Ithaca, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - ICAAAA - Correspondence Received, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Penn Dual Meet, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Intercollegiates, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Correspondence (Track and Field), 1926 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - ICAAAA - Correspondence - carbon copies, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Lists, 1923-1924 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Officials, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Michigan, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Penn Meet, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - ICAAAA Meeting, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - ICAAAA Executive Committee, 1925-1926 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - ICAAAA, 1925-1926 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - ICAAAA, Executive Committee, 1925-1926 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Track Lists, 1925-1926 (Box 2, Folder 2-3)
  - Meet Reports, 1925-1926 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - ICAAAA Indoor Meets, 1925-1926 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Travel Miscellany, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - All-around Jumping and Weight Throwing contests, 1922-1924 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Bradley's Track Collection, Oxford-Cambridge Trip, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Photographs (Box 21)
- Personal
  - Undergraduate Endowment Participation, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - U.E.P. Plan, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - U.E.P. Plan, ca. 1935 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - U.E.P. Plan, ca. 1936 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - The Cornellian council, 1936-1938 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Cornell Alumni Fund, 1938-1939 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Alumni Fund, 1947-1948 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Bradley Personal, 1947-1948 (Box 2, Folder 16-17)
  - (For Archives - originally box 3) (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Alumni Affairs
  - Cornell - Class of '26 Class Dinners at NYCC, 1946-1947 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Class of '26, Treasurer's Information, 1966-1971 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - '26 Reunion Expenses, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - 40th Reunion, Class of '26 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - '26 Reunion costumes, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - '26 Alumni Fund (H.B. file), 1945-1946 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Class of '26 Alumni Fund, 1947-1948 (Box 2, Folder 25-26)
  - Class of '26 Alumni Fund, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 27-29)
  - Class of '26 Alumni Fund, Correspondence, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Class of '26 Alumni Fund, 1946-1947 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Class of '26 Alumni Fund, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - 1926 Data, 1948-1950 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - '26 Reunion Material, 1928, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - '26 10th Reunion, 1930-1936 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Alumni Material and Correspondenc, 1930-1971 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Class of 1897, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Cornell '99 Class Letters, 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Class Newsletters (1912, 1915, 1917, 1922, 1955, 1965) (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - '12 Reunion Material, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Class of 1912 Accounts, 1947-1953 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Class of 1912, Treasurer Boochever, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Class of 1912, Boochever, dues, 1949-1950 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Class of 1912, Boochever, dues, 1951-1952 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Class of 1912, Boochever, dues, 1951-1953 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Class of 1915, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - '15 - 60th Reunion talk, 1915 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Class of 1917, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Class of 1918, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Class of 1922, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Class of 1923, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Class of 1924, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Class of 1925, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Class of 1926, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - "How to Conduct Class Reunions," a paper presented to the American Alumni Council National Conference, July 13, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Class of 1928, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Class of 1931, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Class of 1940, 10th Reunion (Box 3, Folder 3-4)
  - 1940 Men - reunion finances, costume, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Class of 1947, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Quinquennial Reunion Classes, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Reunion Mailings, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Reunion letters - Brewer and Munschauer Promotional Personal, 1950-1952 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Reunion letters, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Class mailings, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Class mailings, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Class mailings, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Reunion, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Reunion Miscellany (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Bradley expense account (Alumni Fund), 1948 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Weekly reports - HHB, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - HHB - Notes, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Murphy, Emmet J., 1948 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Progress at Cornell, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Progress at Cornell - May issue, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Class letters, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 22-23)
  - Alumni Fund, 1948-1956 (Box 3, Folder 24-25)
  - Alumni Fund, 1952-1956 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Alumni Fund, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Alumni Fund, miscellaneous, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Leadership Names - Cornell Fund, 1948-1968 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Lists, 1941-1967 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Guide for Class Officers, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Text - Association of Class Secretaries (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Miscellaneous, ca. 1954-1966 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Ideas for Progress and Report (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Alumni Fund, 1950-1953 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Alumni Fund Council Minutes, 1947-1948 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Cornell Fund Gift Reports, 1958-1961 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Cornell University Council, 1951-1952 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Cornell University Council, 1953-1954 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Cornell University Council, Jan.-May 1955 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Cornell University Council, Sept.-Dec. 1955 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - American Alumni Council Conference notes, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - American Alumni Council, general, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - American Alumni Council Dist. II Conference, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Broadside, Class of '90 - 50th Reunion (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - American Alumni Council, 1955-1959 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Cornell Club of New York, 1946-1948 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Cornell Club of New York, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Lackawanna Cornell Club, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Guide for Cornell Clubs, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Bradley Congratulatory Letters, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Bradley Congratulatory Letters, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 7-9)
  - Gene Kaufmann Memorial Service, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Meade Summers (from), 1923-1926, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Adams, Garner S., 1948 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Snyder, Mrs. Olive N., 1948 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Kiyooka, Eiichi, 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Spear, Robert D. ('19), 1972-1974 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Spear, Robert D., 1975, 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Memoirs of Harold C. Bernhard ('26), ca. 1980 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Di Stasio, Joe ('48), 1947 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Book
  - Bradley book: Her Honor Forever Maintain, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Original longhand text - A (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Original longhand text - B (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Original longhand text - C (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Original longhand text - D (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Alumni Affairs
  - History - Cornell Clubs (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Morris Bishop copy for review, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Harry Kaplan copy for review, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - History - Cornell Alumni Association (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Alumni Association Finances, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Cornell Alumni News (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - History - Cornell Classes (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - History - Cornell Fund (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - History - Cornell Association (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Alumni Conventions (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Alumni Trustee Elections (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Dix Reunion Plan (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Scholarships (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Secondary School Program (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Alumni Institute, 1935-1936 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - A History of Cornell, Bishop (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - History Notes (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - History - footnotes (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - History - Sources of Information (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Miscellaneous History (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - History Chapters (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - History Appendix (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Alumni Association History Index (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Headlines for Montage - History (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - History - Title on cover, Title Page, Frontispiece, Introduction, Dedication, Chapter Heads (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Associate Alumni, 1872-1922 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Cornell Alumni Corporation - Notes on annual meetings, Board of Directors meetings, etc., 1923-1939 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Elements of Style, Strunk, and notes (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Cornell Alumni Association, 1939- (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Bradley's notes on the Associate Alumni Meetings Minutes (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Cornell Conventions, 1917-1942 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - History - Pictures - photo copies, master set #1 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Potential Pictures - extra (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Pictures captions (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - History - Picture references (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - History - correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Transcript of tape recording: Foster Coffin '12 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Transcript of tape recording: Emmet Murphy '22 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Transcript of tape recording: Ray Ashbery '25 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Transcript of tape recording: Max Schmitt '24 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Transcript of tape recording: Olive N. Snyder '22, Walter K. Nield '27, Herman Knauss '27 (no transcript, questions only: Willard Kiggins '21, Francis Eagan '26, Howard Stevenson '19) (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Travel guides and brochures, photos (commercial) (Box 5, Folder 14-15)
  - Cornell postcard views, 1901 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Cornelliana (Box 5, Folder 17-28)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Photograph albums, 1920, 1928, n.d. (Box 6)
  - Photograph albums, 1918-1925 (Box 7)
  - Loose photographs (Box 8-12)
  - Photos and broadsides (Box 13)
  - Scrapbook of newspaper clippings (field and track), 1921 (Box 14)
  - Scrapbook: Elmo Carruthers, England trip, 1926 (Box 15)
  - Scrapbook: Field and Track, 1918-1925 (Box 15)
  - Newsclippings, 1919 (Box 16)
  - Newsclippings, 1917 (Box 16)
  - Newsclippings, 1918 (Box 16)
  - Newsclippings, 1919 (Box 16)
  - Newsclippings, 1935 (Box 16)
  - Track Summary, 1913-1914 (Box 16)
  - Records, 1912 (Box 16)
  - Penn-Cornell Meet, 1942 (Box 16)
  - Cornell Club of New England Minutes, 1924-1938 (Box 17)
  - Cornell Club of Chicago, attendance, 1914-1922 (Box 17)
  - Scrapbook, Cornell 1916 Decennial Reunion, 1925 (Box 17)
  - Glass Slides (Box 18)
  - Rubber Stamp (Box 18)
  - Printing Blocks (Box 18)
  - Glass Lantern Slides (Box 19)
  - Memorabilia: Class of '26 plaque, jacket, cap, buttons; also, brass plated plate from Public Affairs Staff, 1970 (Box 20)
- Tape recordings
  - Foster M. Coffin '12, tr. 4935
  - Emmet J. Murphy '22, tr. 4936
  - Ray Ashbery '25, tr. 4937
  - Max Schmitt '24 and Herman Krauss '24, tr. 4938
  - Olive N. Snyder '22 and Frances Egan '26a, tr. 4939
  - Walter K. Nield '27, tr. 4940
  - Willard Kiggins '21 (no transcript), tr. 4941
  - Ho Ballou tape - old days at Cornell (not for history), tr. 4942
  - Memorial Service for H.H.B., July 7, 1982; tr. 5201a